Like a driving instructor,
I should not exist in your life in six
months.
Why is it so acceptable for people to
invest money into fitness professionals
and
them still be there three years later?
Hmm.
The PT model is almost flawed in some
respects.
If you do your job well enough,
your client leaves.
So for me, even when my clients
that I had face-to-face for years, I
was in the gym
for four years, I said, "Look,
you're going to pay me more than the
rate that you pay anyone else,
but in three months' time,
if you can't do this on
your own,
I'll give you your money back." Because
people arrive at fitness like getting in
the car for the first time.
They're like, "What the hell
is this third pedal?"
Mm.
"That's a clutch." "A clutch? Dad,
what the hell is a clutch?" I remember
learning
to drive. I thought there was go and stop.
And rather than just getting in the car
and driving, I need to explain to them, we
need this to change gears.
The indicator must be done before we start
to brake.
This is your mirrors.
And the fitness world doesn't have
that anymore.
There needs to be some ruthlessness with
this, where I say to people, "Look, this
is the education you need.
You need to learn how to do this for
yourself."